good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to iclc Lombard General
Insurance Company Limited q1 fy24
earnings conference call
from the Senior Management we have with
us today Mr bharco dasgupta MD and CEO
of the company
Mr gopal balachandran CFO and cro
Mr Sanjeev mantri executive director and
Mr alok Agarwal executive director
please note that any statements or
comments made in today's call that may
look like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which could cause results
to defer materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in listen only mode and there will be
an opportunity for you to ask questions
after the presentation concludes should
you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then 0 on your
Touchstone phone
I now run the conference over to Mr
bharatas Gupta ND and CEO ICICI Lombard
General Insurance Limited thank you and
over to you sir
thank you and good evening to each one
of you thank you for joining the
earnings conference call of ICT Lombard
General Insurance Company Limited for q1
fi 2024
I will give you a brief overview of the
industry Trends and developments that we
have witnessed in the past few months
post this our fear for Mr gopal Gala
children will share the financial
performance of the company for the
quarter ended June 302.
domestic demand conditions remain
supportive of growth on the back of
improving household consumption and
investment activity
organ demand remains resident with
indicators such as passenger vehicle
sales and domestic and passenger traffic
posted robust go growth on a
year-on-year basis
this group can have some impact from
headwinds such as weak external demand
volatility Global Financial conditions
and prolonged geopolitical tensions
for the quarters as per data published
by CM the new vehicle sales continue to
grow year on year for private currently
winners however the growth narrowed in
the month of June uh this year the
growth in sales of commercial vehicle
was at a double digit during the quarter
two wheeler sales for the quarter in
terms of volumes remained below the
pre-pandemic levels
health insurance continued to remain the
largest contributor to overall growth
the commercial lines witnessed growth in
with in line with the current market in
the environment
while the fire Market has seen some rate
pressures the inherent growth remains
intact
the focus of the government on
infrastructure has led to a 41.3 growth
during q1 of FY 224 in the engineering
line of business and it's expected to
show encouraging growth in the future as
well
when optimistic that the industry will
continue to grow given Federal favorable
macros regulatory changes low
penetration and positive consumer
sentiment
speaking of the performance The General
insurance industry delivered a gdpi
growth of 17.9 41 of this year overall
the underwriting performance improved
with a combined ratio of the industry at
115.8 foreign
for motor business the combined ratio
for the industry remained elevated at
121.1 for fi 2023 up from 115.6 for fi
2822 combined ratio for model and H1 of
s by 20 2023 was 123.5 which improved to
118.8 for H2 of s523
moving to regulatory upgrades the
authority on June 30th 2023 published
guidelines for remuneration of
non-executive directors and Key
Management personal prescribing limits
on remuneration age engineer
moving to business impact for us in q1
2024 the company grew by 18.9 as
compared to the industry growth of 17.9
excluding crop the company grew by 19.2
percent as against the industry growth
of 17.4 percent
coming to the goals for key segments
during the quarter in Property and
Casualty line of business we grew at
17.0 which is which is higher than the
industry growth of 7.8 percent further
during the quarter we accredited market
share across all segments such as fire
Marine engineering and liability
discontinuance discontinuation of the
iib rates had a moderate impact which is
in line with our expectations however we
will continue to monitor the development
in coming quarters
in motor the growth was stated 5.3 for
the quarter while we grew at 10.8 in
June while we witnessed further we
witnessed month-on-one growth in uh new
Private Car segment during the quarter
with no motor piggy price hike we have
rebalanced our portfolio resulting in a
commercial vehicle makes up 21 and two
wheeler makes at 30.3 percent for q1 of
24.
the health segment continued to be the
fastest growing segment for the industry
during the quarter we grew at 40.4
percent Which is higher than the
industry growth of 20.7 percent
in group health employer employee
segment the change in underlying
industry pricing sentiment resulted in
customers moving towards customers and
close companies with better underwriting
and service capabilities resulting in
our group health segment to go by 43.9
during the quarter
as a result of a continued investment in
retail Health distribution we have
outgrown the industry growth of 18 in q1
24 with the growth of 22.8 percent this
was given by business source through
retail health agency vertical growth of
25.6 percent
I would also like to share that our
One-Stop
solution for all insurance and wellness
need I'll take care of has surpassed 5.6
million user download till date the
incremental download for the quarter was
close to 1 million for q1 of this year
the premium sourced through I'll take
care contributed 58 588.0 million to the
gdpi reflecting uh five times year on
year in increase
our bank issues and key relationship
group uh grew at 27.3 percent this
quarter post pandemic steady credit
growth along with deep Mining and
increase in volunteer and distribution
Partners has been the key growth driver
overall our digital Focus has enabled us
to increase our digital revenues
including I'll take care app revenues to
3.12 billion rupees which are constant
accounts for 4.9 percent of our overall
gdpr for the quarter
we continue to make significant
investments in modernizing our
technology architecture after moving to
the cloud in uh fi 2022 we've modernized
a number of our front-end applications
being on the cloud and transition to to
Cloud native has led to increase in
reliability for technology platforms as
evidenced by the reduction in air
tickets by error tickets by closest 71
this year
in the last year at the same time we
have seen an 86 reduction response times
across of our digital channel partners
our you know responsible intelligent
assistant we call Ria our chatbot has
enabled our DIY adoption by 3.4 times
over a 13-month period
alongside transitioning to the cloud and
modernization we completed the migration
of applications and data from bharti as
a data center to our application
platforms and cloud data center in just
14 months we believe that this was one
of the fastest migrations of this scale
in the insurance industry globally
you also continue to remain focused on
leveraging on digital capabilities and
building claims efficiently
case in point towards model claim
settlement process we introduced Cloud
calling feature enabling over two lab
customers during the quarter to connect
seamlessly using a dedicated virtual
number 81 of our customers filed PK
informant q1 24 up from 67 in q1 of last
year in q1 24 through our PPN Network
the preferred payment garage Network we
were able to service 60 of our non-oem
creams up from 40 in q1 283 resultantly
our overall NPS for non-cational schemes
improved to 62 percent uh for the year
till May 2023 up from 42 for q1 of 23.
also NPS for cashless claims increased
improved to 68 for YTD main 23 up from
60 in q1 of last year
to conclude I would like to summarize
that we are well positioned for the
future we remain focused on growth
levels such as Innovation digital
advancements launching new products
strengthening our distribution engine
rationalizing cost whilst clearing up
our preferred lines of business
I will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
Recently concluded quarter thanks uh
good evening to each one of you I will
now give you a brief overview of the
financial performance of the company for
q1 fy24 we have uploaded the results
presentation on our website you can
access it as we walk you through the
performance numbers
premium income of the company was at
63.87 billion rupees in q1 fi 24 as
against 53.70 billion rupees in q1 f523
a growth of 18.9 against industry growth
of 17.9 excluding crop GDP goes the
company was at 19.2 which was highest in
the industry growth of 17.4 percent in
q1 FY 24.
is primarily driven by growth in the
preferred segments the overall gdpi
growth of our Property and Casualty
segment grew by 17 at rupees 22.86
billion in q1 fy24 as against rupees
19.54 billion in q1 f523 on the retail
side of the business GDP of the motor
segment was at rupees 18.75 billion in
q1 F5 24 as against rupees 17.82 billion
in q1 f523 registering approach of 5.35
Howard aging including the point of sale
distribution count was at one lakh
seventeen thousand one Forty Nine as on
June 30 2023 up from around 1 lakh 13
000 as on March 31 2023 the advanced
premium was rupees 32.63 billion as at
June 30 2023 as against rupees 32.17
billion as at March 31 2023. resultantly
combined ratio was 103.8 for q1 fy24 as
against
104.1 percent for q1 fy23 excluding the
impact of cyclone loss Cyclone losses of
0.35 billion rupees the combined ratio
was 102.9 for q1 fy24
the technical reserves which are
presented as a part of the reserving
disclosures are not discounted as per
the current regulatory framework
however globally we understand
technically reserves technical reserves
are presented on a discounted basis
if we were to Discount the technical
Reserve particularly for the long tail
businesses such as motor third party
which constitutes around 80 percent of
our total outstanding and ibnr Reserves
our current reported combined ratio of
104.5 for FY 2023 would look better by
around 400 basis points our investment
assets Rose to rupees 449.05 billion as
a June 30 2023 from rupees 431.8 billion
as at March 31 2023. our investment
leverage net of borrowings was 4.16
times as at June 30 2023 as against 4.15
times as it March 30 on 2023. investment
income was at RS 8.23 billion in q1 fi
24 as against 36.55 billion in q1 f523
our capital gain stood at rupees 1.23
billion in q1 fy24 as against rupees
0.32 billion in q1 fy23
our profit report tax grew by 11.8
percent at rupees 5.2 billion in q1 fi
24 as against rupees 4.65 billion in q1
f523 consequently profit after tax
proven 11.8 rupees 3.90 billion q1 fy24
as against rupees 3.49 billion in q1
fy23
return on average Equity was 14.7 in q1
FY 24 that's against 15 in q1 and 523 so
almost the ratio was at 2.53 times as at
June 30 2023 as against
2.51 times desert Mass 31 223 continues
to be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times
as I conclude I would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on driving
profitable growth sustainable value
creation and safeguarding interest of
quality holders at all times I would
like to thank you for attending this
earnings call and we will now be happy
to take any questions that you may have
thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and one on their Touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and two
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question to assemble
we have our first question from the line
of paresh Jain from motilal oswal please
go ahead
everyone this is a few few questions
firstly could you talk us through the
loss ratios like uh x catastrophically
what would be the loss ratios and where
is this loss ratio kind of setting so
you might particular group health loss
ratio or a totally help loss ratio is at
78.7 percent could we split that up for
us or you know in terms of code retail
retail health and grouping and there is
this catastrophic we lost exactly
setting in which line item
with all the segments the fresh uh uh in
so far as the breakup of the overall
Health loss ratio numbers that you see
which is 78.7 for q1 fi 24 the breakup
of that for employer employee or the
group health is at about 92.6 percent
the real Indemnity business is at about
64.2 percent so that's the breakup for
the overall health
and your other question in terms of
where is the impact of cyclone losses
largely sitting upon it is predominantly
in the property and the casualty line of
businesses which is In The Fire And
Engineering line of businesses
predominantly a very small proportion of
claims is there in motor but
predominantly a large part of the impact
on the Cyclone is in Fire and
Engineering the combined impact that's
what we give as a part of the opening
remark for this quarter the net impact
of claims on account of cyclone also has
been about 35 crores
okay any reason for this for a very high
loss pressure on the group side is there
a fight in terms of number of planes uh
or frequency or severity
so no specific in general if you see
what we have been speaking about prayers
even in the past on the employer
employee segment generally we have
spoken about the loss ratios to stay in
the range of around that 95 kind of
threshold between 90 to 95.
comprises of two books as what we have
spoken one is relatively large
corporates which kind of runs at a loss
ratio anywhere ranging between 95 to 100
and then we have the relatively SME
which is a small and limit cost rate
portfolio which runs at the loss ratio
experience between 90 to 95. so on
balance historically we have run the
book at a loss ratio as I said around
that 95 threshold
so hence to that extra no specific
changes when we see in the context of
whether let's say an increase in
frequency or increase in severity with
respect to clean
uh that was roughly about 95. so okay
the current quarter is actually lower uh
we don't see any uh any significant
pressure on the health loss ratio side
retail is still performing well and
group health because the cost of
acquisition is low uh this is typically
where the loss issue land
perspective and the mix that you have
change of mix that you've spoken about
to you know going away from commercial
vehicles would that be a strategy for fi
uh or from a longer term perspective and
secondly couldn't talk about you know
like for many quarters we've spoken
about some green shoots on the Audi
pricing uh but you know that's that's
not really reflectingly heavily in terms
of numbers but you mentioned about the
industry loss ratio kind of combination
pandemic uh improving between first half
and second half is there any more uh
clear trends that you know you see
further Improvement or it's just you
know kind of getting arrested at the
current levels
so the first one commercial vehicles uh
I think it's about the uh granular calls
that we took certain strategy because
that we took uh over the last two to
three years which we've talked about I
think we are kind of playing invested
with this with that uh the bit of
rationalizing that we did was because
the PT price high this year didn't
happen so with our estimate of inflation
as we've already always talked about
then certain marginal portfolios being
becoming become unbearable having said
that if you see your 21 percent it's
still higher than what our traditional
TV marketers mix had been which was
about 15 16 and our sense is that we are
not planning to reduce it significantly
it will probably be in the similar
ballpark uh you know 20 plus minus uh
coming to your uh coming to a question
on OD again if you look at uh this
quarter lost issue for us on the OD
compared to last year uh you'll see a
Improvement
having said that uh the expectation that
we've had is some of the aggression on
sourcing side given the expense of
management will cap the flexibility to
some of the players we would we were
expecting some more rationalization some
more Improvement
at this point in this he's not seen it
but I think we are kind of reach the
level where we've uh ironed out most of
the marginal portfolios uh so most of
the pain is behind us
again I request you to join by techusa
thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to answer
queries from all participants please
restrict your questions to two at a time
you may join back the queue for
follow-up questions
we'll take the next question from the
line of sanket Koda from aventus Park
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the opportunity uh
and my question is
[Music]
23 that number is around 67. so just
wanted to understand that this number of
67 is sustainable or or or actually want
to understand more in detail what what
Collective measures you have taken so
that so that except for except for the
choice of not seizing the market share
which has led to the increment in the
into Improvement in the last ratio in
the motor segments that's one one thing
and second just wanted to again
understand if it's the final picture app
which is said today today probably
causes this almost one percentage of
your gdpi
in the copper one you have done so so we
want to understand how how you see this
channel to be a professional channel uh
which products and how much it can
potentially contribute to the entire
entire gwp as time for this
[Music]
that has an impact
so our sourcing uh this is the target
loss issue in this works of business
that is also come out the second is on
the claim side there's been a huge
amount of effort that we have done more
in terms of some of the abuse that was
that that generally happens but we
believe had picked up post covered
um so on the claims control we've done a
lot of work on using data analytics uh
to uh reduce waste and abuse uh thirdly
we talked about the percentage increase
in PPN that also gives us some Savings
of the claim site so the multiple
initiatives that has happened and you
know is it sustainable again we'll have
to wait to see Market conduct but we are
reasonably hopeful that we should be
able to sustain this at this current
level uh coming to your point on I'll
take care the number that we gave out
it's about five times of last year's
similar number for the quarter but in
aggregate for the company even if we add
this I'll take a number to the overall
digital business it's as we said it's
about 4.9 percent of our uh of our total
business let's see I'll take care of a
contribution for this quarter was about
58 crores 588 million so it's not a
material number as yet but we believe
this is actually helping us at multiple
levels one is uh customer engagement
retention we see some loss you know
better loss ratio for clients which use
I'll take care in group levels we see a
better retention of uh you know
profitable accounts in the Corpus
trading we are looking at how we can use
this further strategically in terms of
increasing uh crosstalk and upsell uh
that's working progress but still
honestly in terms of aggregate numbers
we are very hardened by the scale uh the
speed at which it's speaking up but uh
small in the overall scheme of things
you know private cars we are seeing uh
employees of uh you know corporates
buying policies uh on their own so it's
a mix of uh most products that we have
there
to the commission
so I think for kids uh if you regret
racing the behavior always talked about
this I think to look at the businesses
from an overall combined perspective
because as we keep saying there are
different models of sourcing that exist
in the market I mean there are segments
which relatives run on INR and low
extensive management and and the other
way around so which is what now when you
look at let's say even from a quarter
one perspective I think I would kind of
always keep urging to look at it more
from an expensive management standpoint
rather than looking at uh any breakups
uh around that so if you look at the
overall expense of management in terms
of the breakup of the combined issue
that we reported about 103.8 percent for
quarter one of which the loss ratio was
about 74.1 percent and the balance which
is almost about 29.7 is the uh expensive
Management number this if you look at it
for quarter one of last year the
expensive Management number was about
32.1 percent
and uh again when you look at it even
visibly quarter four quarter four the
expensive Management number was about
29.9 so even on a sequential basis I
think we have seen an improvement in the
overall expenses management and even on
a year-on-year business I think clearly
there have been an improvement in the
overall expense of management that's the
way we would want you to look at because
as I said there are different models of
sourcing that exist and and as a company
that's what you would want to kind of
look at
thanks
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
nidesh Jain from investex please go
ahead
so if you look at the very uh manage
this business there is uh the digital
one team which looks at if you remember
we had said there are two uh objectives
that we they have one is uh the website
business growth and the other is working
with the digital ecosystem partners
and we look at it together that that
good for this quarter is about 37.8
percent
uh the I'll Take Care number as we said
is relatively small but that's grown
from a small base at five times
four hundred percent
I think last year uh in public
disclosure the data indicates that the
road from our own website has not been
that strong it has been letting out uh
growth is largely coming from the
digital ecosystem so are those Trends
continuing in this quarter also or uh
and because because the company is
coming from our own website will be much
more uh much more better quality though
much more profitable than probably over
a period of time and so how we think
about the strategy and digital side from
school uniform website
so obviously we look at all of them are
preferred channels of sourcing whether
you look at business through website
business through alliances and even
let's say the I'll take care opportunity
has what uh balza explained for us all
the three segments have grown uh whether
you look at it from a threat standpoint
whether you look at it even from an
alliance standpoint in fact during the
quarter we have further strengthened the
number of alliances types that we have
and that's the reason why that part is
that that part of the business has done
uh phenomenally quite well and overall
as we said the digital one contribution
in terms of revenue for the company for
this water has grown at about 24.7
percent
so a secondly uh last year we put out a
strategy that we will focus on higher
loss ratio and low Opex ratio business
in the motor only segment
uh so how why did you look at that loss
ratios have improved uh quite a bit and
offense ratio has also seen some
improvement uh so how is the uh how is
the trend there there
how the share of that business is
setting up on overall mobile
is what I would say I think what we put
out as a part of our opening remarks I
think for us if you look at this
particular quarter I think the growth on
new private car has kind of come back uh
which is kind of exhibited when you look
at it sequentially on a month-oldness
basis I think the growth in new private
cars seems to be kind of doing well I
think that and that typically also comes
with a relatively better loss experience
having said that I think we are also
kind of increasingly focusing on exactly
the point that you mentioned with
respect to focusing on relatively older
vehicle segments which also comes with a
relatively High LR and let's say a lower
cost of acquisition and that's again
this lifting also in the expense of
Management number
and if you recreate what we have been
talking about historically our
proportion of motor business coming in
through the OEM channel of contribution
used to be in the range of 75 to 80
percent increasingly that proportion of
contribution of business of motor coming
in from let's say the OEM Channel
distribution which will be in the range
of about 60 60 papers so directionally I
think what we have been trying to do is
to balance the overall portfolio between
contribution from OEM dealership agency
as well as the earlier point that we
made in terms of the digital
opportunities
thank you
we have our next question from the line
of Shreya Shivani from clsa please go
ahead
yeah hi thank you I have two questions
first is on the motor segment a total
motor segment so uh if I compare uh
Lombards both loss ratio and growth
across the private peers I would uh
specifically look at the private General
insurance so many of them would have
just a few percentage Point higher loss
ratio on this segment uh but they are
they're delivering about
you know 15 growth uh in this quarter as
per the AI data so what can be what can
we expect for Lombard uh Lombard's motor
segment for the full year and any
guidance on the over pre overall premium
growth for fy24 at 524 that's the first
question and uh the second question is
uh on the crop loss ratio it seems a
little higher uh at more than 100 and
last year I remember you guys had shared
that
um the crop program that you had
participated in was a 80 120 cap plan
something like that so if you can help
us understand
so so the second part is
uh answer that Shreya so in general if
you recollect uh obviously the claim
development Cycle takes time and that's
the reason uh from our conservical
standpoint whenever we book the revenues
given that we don't have complete
experience of loss development we end up
providing it to 100 uh loss ratio basis
so which is why when you look at that
numbers uh you will find a lot of
pressures to be a bit elevated but when
you when the actual experience starts to
kind of play out you will obviously
start getting that uh reflector on
actuals so hence typically it roughly
takes about two quarters for the loss
development to play out in the crop
segment so as and when we get to see the
impact of the cycle we will kind of
actualize those numbers
your first point on what is it that we
can expect on overall growth for the
company as a whole I think in line with
what we have spoken uh as we always keep
saying the market needs to get better in
terms of pricing uh at this point of
time if you would have seen for quarter
one I think we have had almost close to
almost about 200 basis points South
performance ability to the market growth
numbers when you look at X of crop uh
and so that's really the expectation
that we have at the company we have we
have the necessary strength in so far as
distribution claim service and
technology is concerned and hence to
that extent from an overall
Market standpoint we would obviously
want to expect us continue to have
similar kind of uh outperformance now
within that your first point on how does
one see on motor as I said again when
you look at it on sequential which is
month on month I think clearly we have
been able to possibly arrest the extent
of uh regrowth that we had seen in that
particular segment so for example in
April we had a d growth in a motor for
the month of May we had a positive
growth about five percent and for the
month of June we had a growth of almost
about 10 so frequency rating I think we
have been able to kind of get better and
the extent of gap between the industry
growth numbers and let's say the growth
that we have been exhibiting is kind of
getting narrowed down
the only thing that would watch out for
to your point on what we could expect
for the rest of the year is
the the adherence to the extensive
management guidelines that's coming to
post from this year in fact I was just
when we were looking at the FI 23
numbers that's now out for the entire
Market as a whole almost close to
two-thirds of the industry participants
have their expensive Management number
greater than the regulatory prescribed
limit of 30 or 35 percent
so this clearly calls for an action
which is what I presume even the
regulator will be significantly uh
putting a focus on once all companies
start putting out their q1 numbers I'm
sure they will start looking at the
expensive management numbers for the
overall Market as a whole and within
that each individual companies in terms
of how they are exhibited and uh once
some of these things starts to correct
uh over the period of time obviously as
I said it's so far as our positioning is
concerned I think we should be able to
kind of uh see a relatively better
growth uh even in motor essay category
I mean you know you can do the analysis
yourself adding third party uh again if
you do a bit deeper dive on the
reserving picture which is now available
to all of you you'll be able to figure
out the reserving practices and that
will probably throw some light on the
loss ratio numbers of some of the
players in the market
so one uh one just uh a clarification I
wanted uh the retail Indemnity loss
ratio that you mentioned at 64.2 uh this
is 64.2 for the retail Indemnity sold by
agents or the ones which is the one
which is getting sold by ICS
and what is the loss ratio of the icsi
bank
portion that is getting sold by itself
that's not fair on the distributor also
okay thank you
thank you
we have our next question from the line
of Rishi junjunwala from iifl
institutional equities please go ahead
yeah thanks for the opportunity this
couple of questions firstly on the
health side so um can you tell us about
uh you know in the you know detail held
the 23 we are only abroad that we have
seen how much of that is driven by
pricing increase that we have taken in
February and secondly on the corporate
side there is a significant growth that
has come here
um you know is that being driven by
um you know the the normal group health
plans or there is a large component of
um you know the credit protect plans
also which are coming here and and is
that the reason why unexpired risk
Reserve has shorter significantly for us
in this quarter
so the second part krishi uh to your
point on the uh
one on the I'll just kind of talk about
the commercial lines as the category and
within that then I will talk about your
corporate health or let's say the group
health uh point that you wanted to
understand or across commercial lines I
think we have actually been able to
exhibit significant market share and
what we kind of also put out as a part
of the opening remarks in fact relative
to an industry growth of which is single
digit 7.8 our growth has been about 17
and this fans across fire Marine
engineering liability etc etc across the
key commercial line and there the growth
is aided by uh across all factors which
is it is driven by volume increase this
is equally driven by I would say a
creation of market share and
specifically now also in the context of
corporate Health we have also been able
to see accretion in pricing as well so
it's been an all-round kind of growth
that one has seen in the overall
commercialized portfolio
your second point on now within the
group health or let's say within the
corporate Hill again it's been a
combination of both uh we have uh I
actually would kind of recollect uh some
of the participants in the market and it
exhibited significant handwriting losses
particularly in the hospital space and
there have been clear instructions that
they have given to their respective
operating officers to get better on
underwriting so that's exactly is what
we kind of wait for as opportunities for
us to kind of write businesses because
as I said we have the necessary back end
uh strength in terms of distribution and
uh let's say claim service to our
advantage so hence we have been able to
gain a great market share uh from some
of those companies into us where
customer starts to look at more in terms
of service uh as the basis of placing uh
the risk so and the growth is aided by a
Christian and market share again volume
we do see in some sectors incremental
hiring being done by some of the
corporate concerns and then to that
extent it is also volume driven and
three it's also a function of fact as I
said the relative overall growth that
one has seen uh health is also aided by
I would say uh reasonable growth even on
the bank insurance State as we are kind
of put out given as a part of the
opening remarks or Bank insurance which
comprises of distribution through banks
and our key relationship group Partners
that's again done reasonably well uh at
almost about 27 growth uh on the back of
again uh reasonable growth coming back
in terms of credit uh disbursement what
one would watch for is obviously the
extent of disbursement levels as we head
into the subsequent quarters I think
that we will wait for in terms of all
the development takes place
understood and second question you know
why you explained about the expensive
management thing and you know that you
look at on an overall basis and that's
when it is what we are going to do but
just from a purpose of understanding uh
wanted to understand the change in um
commission and the business promotion
um is it purely a reclassification issue
from books of accounts perspective from
the way you are now paying to the
distributors or is there any actually on
ground business model changed also
I think at the end of the day we always
look at the overall cost of acquisition
in terms of the way we kind of uh do
businesses and that's the reason why I
kind of specifically put out that number
in the context of expensive management
and that's what I would urge to kind of
look at and honestly the kind of split
between what constitutes commission what
constitutes let's say My overall
operating expenses all of them are
patreon as a part of our operating model
fundamentally if you ask us have you
changed anything in so far as the
underlying way of doing business
honestly not there is no specific change
that one has kind of done and hence
which is why I'm saying that once you
start looking at the numbers more from
an expensive management standpoint
rather than trying to look at splits
between how much has been the growth in
commissions and how much has been the
changes in operating access
thank you thank you
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
Avinash Singh from MK Global please go
ahead
yes good evening ask two questions or
the first one is more on a commercial
line uh you're particularly fire
engineering so they were sort of a
mythical factors affecting the pricing
and all so just I mean if you can give
some color on that addressing for your
Cyclone losses if there has been sort of
an impact on overall of claims ratio
because of the pricing environment or it
will quantify also the price changes
effectively that happened in this water
so that's on Commercial line second on
Group Health or employed
you can provide some sort of uh you know
either quantify you for some qualitative
disclosure in terms of how has been your
experience on the uh you know uh
business that you had initially acquired
a pre-covered period and continue to
renew I mean besides
and the business you're required or say
last year so are there sort of a
difference in terms of the claims
experience in these two sets if we are
two questions thank you
so uh let me take the second one and
gopal can give you the split of uh let's
say the commercialized visit in
Aggregates the commercial and business
there's been some uh softening on the
Fireside for the reasons that we've been
talking about which is that the IRB rate
is no longer there but it's a
it's well in line with our estimates so
it's a single digit change not a
material reduction that we have seen in
the first quarter but we'll have to Be
watchful of how this progress is uh for
the recipient but till now it's largely
been you know in line with expectation
the difference in the uh you know the
loss ratios for fire and Engineering
without with and without cat gopal will
uh
coming back to your question on Group
Health Avinash uh I think the real good
news for us was that you know the
accounts that we had pre-covered you
know and we've been talking about this
in the past as well
uh you know from July of the year after
the first second wave we started
increasing prices by between 15 to 20
and we used to see almost 90 percent
more than 90 retention of the large
accounts so I think the service
proposition that we've delivered uh you
know the the various uh features of
anti-care Etc I think overall we've had
good experience in terms of weakening
these accounts uh this year uh for the
reasons that gopal explained we are
seeing a good Traction in business
moving from uh some of the other uh you
know companies that come coming in the
way we are pricing it is again in line
with our you know general practice of
being uh disciplined about underwriting
so the question then is that will these
guys also be new next year python go now
that we have to wait for but the
approach that we take is even only going
with any of these accounts the approach
is to look at customers who are not uh
you know price speakers everywhere who
switched from one company to other but
to look at companies who've generally
been stable with one insurer for some
time maybe we're wanting to move now
because of service experiences or
because pricing has signed between the
go up and come close to our numbers and
we are able to get a slight premium over
the market prices so on balance I don't
see a big difference between the
accounts that we had in the past to the
accounts that we have got now
yeah and uh vinash to your point on uh
what could be the potential impact on
some of this pricing LED changes and
let's say a cyclone net impact right I
think so far as the price decline it's a
single digit number roughly in that
range of I would say between five to
seven percent kind of decline in pricing
it's what one had seen and that's on
expected lines that's what we had
mentioned even during the April earnings
fall at the time when the guidelines had
come into Force which is the reason why
if you see for overall Market fire
growth for quarter one is far more rapid
at let's say 5.9 or six percent uh even
despite that if you look at for ice is a
long word we can add an out performance
in that category
on the other part what we discussed even
in the April earnings call if you
recollect is also the hardening of
reinsurance rates and therefore to that
extent we also had seen an improvement
increase in the XML costs what
effectively happens is the NEP does a
catch up because typically your cost of
X will start creative in quarter one and
has the book kind of grows the earnings
play through over the remaining quarters
so now when you look at the loss ratios
what is put out in the invested day for
fire next day at about 85 for quarter
one and let's say 98.6 for engineering
now this has the impact of the actual
cost it also has the impact of I would
say losses from Cyclone as what I kind
of mentioned uh very difficult to kind
of separately call out the impact of the
actual cost but if everybody just
exclude the impact of cyclone losses the
loss ratio on fire which is at about 85
will look like about 64 65 and
Engineering which is looking like about
98.6 will look like about close to about
80 82 in that range so that's the kind
of numbers that one sees in so far as
excluding the catalysters are concerned
but as I said q1 uh particularly for
engineering is relatively more long tail
as the project starts to kind of build
over a period of time with where you
will see a relatively larger proportion
of earnings coming through and hence
that section you will always find
possibly the q1 loss ratios to be a bit
more skilled
okay okay so I mean
90 broadly is for your old book as well
as new book I mean
I request you to join that the queue
says there are the participants waiting
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
swarna Mukherjee from bnk Securities
please go ahead
yeah hi sir thank you for the
opportunity uh so a couple of questions
uh first on the retail helmet so some
you mentioned around 64-ish ratio in the
retail individual portfolio
um this I was just wondering that
historically you have told that you have
run this book at allowance and lost
initiated between 65 to 70 so is there a
possibility that will uh push the
federal a little bit more in terms of
growth uh going ahead so that we are in
between that Mark because profitability
wise I think we are much better than
where we were running the business so
whether we should expect to see the
group finding out at a faster rate and
uh you know much much more higher than
the industry even better market share is
still lower than what our company
agreement here is uh across category so
that is the first question on retail
room uh and then the second question of
on the fire loss ratios you pointed out
that there are excellent losses that are
breaking right now just wanted to
understand that is there you know given
that a negative health ratio there that
you have reported uh if uh if we were to
remove the impact of xol losses also how
should we also see some agreement of
that deregulation playing out in the
loss ratio in terms of uh you know uh
denominator
from the pricing point of view and
currently on on the crop premium for the
month of June I think there was a
sizeable crop premium so that pertains
to Maharashtra and of a similar
structure of what it was done last year
uh so that okay let me let me add to the
file that we they get uh to cover the
rest and as gopal explained the the
ratio for those two businesses look a
bit elevated but we are very comfortable
and very happy with the book as we
explained a big chunk of that
incremental loss issues because of cap
which happens once in a while secondly
the Sprite softening has had a five to
six percent impact not not as big as one
was worrying about so in that sense is
the positive third is the soil cost is
an upfront cost as we go through the
year the energy keeps accitting and the
actual cost gets spread over the whole
12 months so if you wanted to look
elevated because
it's a smaller book through you know
which is kind of uh absorbing that
increment so I think overall our
Property and Casualty business we are
very happy with the way things are
progressing just to give you an overall
sense of where we see the business
follow up follow up on that the price
opening part that you mentioned five to
six percent so in in a scenario if the
insurance Market kind of softens is here
from where it is can can it uh act this
occurring can be moved now
you know Realms of speculation uh you
know too many factors are unknown in the
global reinsurance markets so there's no
point in talking about right now maybe
we can discuss this pose generally one
uh so that's the catch-up that will
start to happen and this is not just
specific to any particular segment I
think for across segments when we kind
of exhibit growth we will start seeing
anything doing a catch-up over the
subsequent quarters so which is what you
should kind of watch out for and
actually always keep saying
for us you should ideally look at
outcomes over years
uh if not ideally on a financial year
basis definitely not quarters I mean
quarters will have lots of elements
attached to it and again we will urge
everyone to keep looking at numbers more
on annual basis ideally over years
because that's how the insurance Cycles
typically work so that's just in
addition to what Margo said to your
third point on the crop I think uh
pretty much similar to what we have been
talking uh which is even the one that we
have won in Maharashtra that again
operates under the 1800 engine model uh
which is where we are kind of clear
about what kind of risk that we want to
undertake and two as we have discussed
even during the April call potentially
there is an expectation that this year
could be in a year of early enough and
as to that extent again from an exposure
standpoint I think we would want to be a
bit guarded and even otherwise what we
have said uh even uh earlier as well on
crop relative to our overall numbers I
would definitely want to say that less
than five percent of the aggregate
annual revenues so that stands kind of
pretty much Remains the Same
uh to your first point on the overall
retail Health loss ratios again I mean
this is quarter one numbers right uh I
think the range that we gave is the
range that we are comfortable to kind of
operate with uh asset segment and what
we are quite happy and excited about is
the fact that even if you look at
consistently since uh I would say second
half of last year uh and even for the
whole of in fact fy23 we are all we have
had our performance on retail Health
visit with the market I mean if you
recollect for fi 23 our growth was
almost about 17 industry on retailers
through at 15. even quarter one when you
look at the numbers for us individual or
retailers grew at almost about 23 market
growth was about 18 19 so again we have
had outperformance relative to the
overall Market the good news is even
when you look at it in the context of
standard on health companies our growth
in quarter one has largely been in line
with the Standalone Health growth
numbers as well so hence to that extent
whatever investment that we're doing on
retail Health we are quite excited with
the way how the Investments have played
out and that's the reason why you
already start to see some small levels
of increase in market share that we have
seen uh which used to be sub three
percent right now we are at about first
about three point one second market
share in the retail Health internet
of course as you rightly said there's a
lot of ketchup that we have to do and
hence to that extent we will continue to
stay invested in building that
distribution force and uh and loss
ratios as I said will be more and the
range is what we kind of largely talked
about q1 honestly again very difficult
to comment on one particular quarter you
have to ideally look at it more on a
full year basis
understood
I request you to join back the queue sir
thank you
we have a next question from the line of
prakar Sharma from Jeffries please go
ahead
thank you and congratulations to all of
you I just wanted to get a pulse of you
know this flooding in the northern
Indian part how big is the business how
should we kind of uh assess any
potential loss that's part one and just
wanted to get a sense on you know the
full year and next year combined ratio
of you know expectation are we you know
sticking to our real guidance so these
were my precautions thank you
so uh the second uh one ingredient to
answer yes we are speaking to it uh
instead of these losses that cat losses
that we had in this quarter and the the
North Indian floods will come in the Q2
because these were not I mean even now
as we speak uh the losses are coming in
till now it doesn't look to be
significantly uh you know an area of
concern uh but it's too early to call
prakar I think we'll you know what
happens in the clubs is that it takes
some time for the customers to come back
and report all the claims
you have to wait for some time
but whatever it is uh you know as a
company
unless these losses are significantly
out of uh think with the past
experiences I think we'll be we are
clear that we are staying within the
same guidance levels that we talked
about
thank you thank you thank you best of
luck
thanks thank you
we have our next question from the line
of neeraj toshniwal from UBS Indies go
ahead yeah hi uh so given you have to do
some women rule in motor which is quite
impressive uh one didn't understand we
outlooked going ahead and are we seeing
uh some kind of rising improvements
which will happen to do a sense of
managing
changes and uh no height in uh motor CP
pricing for this year
as we said on the second Point not much
we have expected some more Improvement
because of expensive management uh you
know constraints uh it seems some you
know bit of correction in terms of
certain elements of you know PA price
etc for this Etc so a lot of companies
have improved some element of the
pricing but it's not to the extent that
one had a you know expected given the
expense of management as gopal explained
uh you know for a large number of
companies in the sector they are over
their limit as of now we've not seen a
change but as we explained we'll have to
see what happens after quarter one and
how the regulator looks at industry
numbers and Company specific numbers You
Will Be watchful from our perspective we
are well within the limit
we have the cushion but that's doesn't
mean that we are going to be profligated
we are focusing on building a
sustainable business
so what kind of growth in motor
portfolio we are kind of now uh given
the momentum is coming back we are
building in
so I think as I said earlier I think the
the
difficult part is behind us is what we
think so our expectation is that we
should definitely go and buy into the
market for this quarter
and uh the last questions
on that
should so nearly I think uh I think this
is something that we have been talking
about uh
as well so obviously at an appropriate
point of time I think as we keep saying
uh suppression planning is something
that actively gets discussed at the bnrt
and at the board level uh across
management level so maybe at an
appropriate time I think we will come
back uh if at all uh wherever we have to
make any necessary announcements
foreign
I think they will announce it whenever
they're ready to announce it yeah we
will have to wait for to get all the
approvals but they've got enough time to
to do the same as of now there we are
vaping all clearances
Thank you
Rich thanks thank you
ladies and gentlemen that was the last
question for today I now hand the
conference over to Mr barkada's Gupta
for closing comments over to you sir
thank you thank you everyone for joining
and look forward to uh you know be
interacting with you over the next few
days feel free to reach out to us thank
you again thank you so much thank you on
behalf of ICICI Lombard General
Insurance company that concludes this
conference thank you for joining us and
even after